<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portkey</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portkey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 17:49:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Network Address Translation and How Does It Work?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-network-address-translation-and-how-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 17:49:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-network-address-translation-and-how-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Network Address Translation (NAT) and Its Uses In today’s networking environments, Network Address Translation (NAT) plays a crucial role in connecting devices and maintaining network security. This article will explore what NAT is, the different types of NAT, and how it is used in various network scenarios. What is Network Address Translation (NAT)?&#xA;Network Address Translation (NAT) is a method used by routers to translate private (non-routable) IP addresses within a local network to a single public IP address before sending traffic to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding DHCP: The Magic Behind Automatic IP Assignment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-dhcp---the-magic-behind-automatic-ip-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 21:26:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-dhcp---the-magic-behind-automatic-ip-assignment/</guid>
      <description>In the world of network engineering, DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) is a crucial service that makes our lives a lot easier. But what exactly is DHCP, and how does it work? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details and explore the ins and outs of this essential network service. What is DHCP?&#xA;DHCP stands for Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s a network management protocol used to automate the process of configuring devices on IP networks, allowing them to use network services such as DNS, NTP, and any communication protocol based on UDP or TCP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Routing Protocols: BGP</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/dynamic-routing-protocols---bgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:51:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/dynamic-routing-protocols---bgp/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into something that&amp;rsquo;s at the core of how the internet works: BGP, or Border Gateway Protocol. If you’ve ever wondered how data finds its way across the globe, BGP is a big part of that magic. Think of BGP as the postal service of the internet. Just like how postal services route your mail through various cities to get it to its destination, BGP routes data between different networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Different Network Designs: LAN and WAN</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/exploring-different-network-designs---lan-and-wan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:32:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/exploring-different-network-designs---lan-and-wan/</guid>
      <description>In network engineering, the design of a network is pivotal to its efficiency, scalability, and reliability. Different types of network designs cater to various needs, from local area networks (LAN) to wide area networks (WAN). In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into several LAN designs, such as three-tier, collapsed core, campus, and spine-and-leaf architectures, as well as WAN designs like hub-and-spoke and mesh. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the pros and cons of each to help you make informed decisions for your network infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running Ollama AI in Your Homelab</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/running-ollama-ai-in-your-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:26:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/running-ollama-ai-in-your-homelab/</guid>
      <description>Ollama https://ollama.com/&#xA;Ollama is a platform designed to run AI models locally. It offers a streamlined experience for deploying and managing AI applications without requiring extensive cloud resources. Ollama supports a variety of models and provides tools for easy integrations and monitoring.&#xA;Ollama installation Starting out, we will be installing this into an Ubuntu virtual server. I am running Ubuntu server 22.04 on my local Proxmox server. once you have your base Ubuntu server ready to go, installing Ollama is super simple, we will just follow the Download instructions found on https://ollama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 13:12:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I’m Bryan Wassel, a passionate network engineer with over 15 years of experience in the IT industry, including more than 6 years specializing in Network Engineering. I have a knack for making complex systems simple and reliable, and I’ve had the pleasure of working on a variety of exciting projects that have sharpened my skills and expanded my knowledge.&#xA;At Portkey, my goal is to create a space where people can learn and explore different topics in network engineering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Trunk Ports</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-trunk-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 21:56:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-trunk-ports/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of network engineering, understanding the distinction between different types of ports is fundamental. Among these, trunk ports play a crucial role in managing network traffic efficiently and securely. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into what a trunk port is, how it differs from an access port, and its importance in network infrastructure. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover best practices for configuring trunk ports to ensure optimal security and performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a VLAN</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-a-vlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 11:50:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-a-vlan/</guid>
      <description>VLAN stands for Virtual Local Area Network. Think of it as a way to segment a physical network into smaller, isolated parts without needing separate physical switches for each segment. It&amp;rsquo;s like having a bunch of invisible walls inside your network that can help organize and secure your traffic.&#xA;Why Use VLANs? Organization: Imagine your office building. Without VLANs, it’s like having no cubicles or offices—just one giant room where everyone’s talking over each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking for AI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/networking-for-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:12:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/networking-for-ai/</guid>
      <description>AI has become a significant force in the market, reshaping how people perceive technology. While I enjoy using AI models to craft images and descriptions for my D&amp;amp;D group, immortalizing our adventures, my interaction with AI has been limited to this recreational use. Professionally, as a network engineer, my involvement with AI models is mostly limited to drawing inspiration from them for new ideas, or getting help rewording my emails and other communications.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
