<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Portkey</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Portkey</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:56:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Trunk Ports</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-trunk-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:56:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/understanding-trunk-ports/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Trunk Ports: A Key Component in Network Engineering&#xA;In the realm of network engineering, understanding the distinction between different types of ports is fundamental. Among these, trunk ports play a crucial role in managing network traffic efficiently and securely. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into what a trunk port is, how it differs from an access port, and its importance in network infrastructure. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover best practices for configuring trunk ports to ensure optimal security and performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is a VLAN</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-a-vlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 11:50:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/what-is-a-vlan/</guid>
      <description>VLAN stands for Virtual Local Area Network. Think of it as a way to segment a physical network into smaller, isolated parts without needing separate physical switches for each segment. It&amp;rsquo;s like having a bunch of invisible walls inside your network that can help organize and secure your traffic.&#xA;Why Use VLANs? Organization: Imagine your office building. Without VLANs, it’s like having no cubicles or offices—just one giant room where everyone’s talking over each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking for AI</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/networking-for-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:12:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/networking-for-ai/</guid>
      <description>AI has become a significant force in the market, reshaping how people perceive technology. While I enjoy using AI models to craft images and descriptions for my D&amp;amp;D group, immortalizing our adventures, my interaction with AI has been limited to this recreational use. Professionally, as a network engineer, my involvement with AI models is mostly limited to drawing inspiration from them for new ideas, or getting help rewording my emails and other communications.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
